We really figured out very quickly, again, that we couldn't do anything on three acres.
So the next best thing that we could do was, again, enact this educational framework and put it into the community's hands.
Nine times out of 10, it was donation-based classes.
But we were trying to get them the information so they can be comfortable growing their own food and then mesh together as a support network.
Yes.
Right?
Hyperlocal food system.
So traveling back to that route, so we more so started educating all of our community members, people in the neighborhood, the kids, the schools, in order to create a network of growers, bakers, and makers so that when we wanted to boycott or we wanted a different option or we wanted to not have to read all the ingredients on the back of the label and pull out Google to see what this word means.
So we really had a support network that we had decentralized and we didn't have to bear the burden of everything.
So that's kind of where our transition happened.
I get really irritated when people say to me, like, we don't have leaders.
Where are the leaders at?
And we have people like yourself.
This is an example of leadership.
For so many people, their only idea of leadership is leading a march.
This right here is an actual example of leadership, you all, because what it is, is demonstrating values carried out through action, disseminated through community.
And it is done so in direct opposition to the framework that is in place to repress.
It's not done like, we're just doing it.
It's like, no big deal.
No, it is actively done in resistance.
Yes.
Very calculated.
Very strategic.
So that leads us to collectively sustainable, which is our, it used to be a grassroots movement, but now through our expansion, we are a social impact movement.
And again, that framework that was used for the kids that subsequently were used for the adults is now being disseminated nationwide to our other stewardship centers is what we call it.
So our farm operates as an educational green space to where, again, the community can come in.
So anybody who has the space, the time, the bandwidth, the wherewithal to kind of do what we're doing in their backyard, their community garden, their homestead, their farm, we're encouraging them to be a resource for their community by way of collectively sustainable becoming a stewardship center.